《诉讼双雄》前情提要
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
你不能把孩子的需求置于自己之上
You can't put the needs of our child above your own.
-我不是这个意思  -那你什么意思
- I'm not saying that. - Then what are you saying?
首席翻译官
█ 网易见外
因为虽然我还不是母亲
Because I may not be a mother yet,
但我知道那是父母的义务
but I know that's what parenthood means.
你想跟我开战  你尽管来
You wanna take me on, you go for it.
首席校对官
人人译视界
·
人人
因为我坐的这个位子
'Cause I didn't get where I am
可不是随便让人威胁拿来的
by letting people like you push me around.
大卫·福克斯想打一架
David Fox wants a fight,
翻译     Alex 辰星晓Reginamoon 木浅 arcadiachi 爱爬树的小猴子
我会和他奉陪到底
and I'm gonna give him one.
你是在拿我的工作威胁我吗
Are you threatening my job?
我一向欣赏你
I like you, always have.
但是如果你在这件事上做不对的话
But if you don't get yourself on the right of this thing,
翻译     阿序 不見曦月 海云生 暴走小罐头 苏葵
你不会比你现在的位置走得更远了
you're never gonna go further than you are right now.
我关心他们  慈善机构本该照顾好他们
I care about the kids this charity is supposed to serve.
校对     木浅
但你不会知道因为我不...
But you wouldn't know that because I just don't...
-信任...  -其他人
- trust... - People.
时间轴     知之    Caroline
你是说你换工作了
Are you saying you took another job?
不  是我让某人换了份工作
No, I'm saying I got someone else to take another job.
你还是没做我吩咐的事情
You still didn't do what I asked.
后期     斯人
我签了一个将来会对律所
I signed a client that's gonna be worth
有巨大价值的客户
a huge amount to this firm.
我是个出色的律师
I'm a hell of a goddamn lawyer.
总监     木浅
付他们应得的工资...
You start paying those people what they're worth...
然后呢
And?
你将得到为期一年的哈维·斯佩克特的
You get free legal services from Harvey Specter himself
┌
┐
└
┘
人人影视官方客户端
唯一下载渠道
app.YYeTs.com
┌
┐
└
┘
免费法律咨询服务
for the next year.
你都没发现你的重要律师
You didn't notice that one of your star attorneys
都在考虑辞职了
was thinking about leaving.
多亏了我
And now, thanks to me,
他才考虑留下
he's gonna stay.
-你在说亚历克斯吗  -而有时候
- You're talking about Alex. - Sometimes,
你需要让我们按我们的方式来办事
you need to let us do what we do the way we do it.
你好  陌生人...  我最近一次见到你
Hello, stranger... seems the only thing
好像还是在
I see of you lately
刻有你名字的墙上
is your name on the wall.
那是因为我这些天出门有点事
That's because I've been out of town a few days,
我需要你的帮助
and I need your help.
说吧
Give it to me.
我遇到了法律问题  是个人私事
I've got a legal situation, and it's personal.
也就是说你想让我
Which means you need me
派一个我们的律师过去
to send one of ours your way.
我想让亚历克斯·威廉姆斯来
I was thinking Alex Williams.
你介意我问一下吗
Would you mind if I ask
你为什么不自己给他打电话
why you didn't just call him yourself?
我一直在想
I was thinking about
几周前我们的那次谈话
a conversation we had a few weeks ago.
你让我懂得了关于促进律所和谐的问题
You helped me see some things about fostering firm harmony.
如果你直接打电话给他
And if you called him directly,
你就没机会把这些话告诉我
you wouldn't have had a chance to tell me that.
又被你猜对了  唐娜
Right again, Red.
我猜你选亚历克斯而不是萨曼莎
I'm guessing firm harmony is also why
也是出于律所和谐的原因
you want Alex and not Samantha.
有这方面的考虑
A little bit of that,
也是因为和案子情况有关
and a little of the nature of the case.
那不如告诉我你在哪  还有你
Then why don't you tell me where you are,
亚历克斯需要准备的东西  我会保证
what Alex needs to bring, and I will make sure
他马上行动
that he is on his way.
哈维·斯佩克特
Harvey Specter.
大卫·福克斯
David Fox.
我真的太
To what do I owe the--
荣幸的反义词是什么来着
what's the opposite of pleasure?
我来这里是为了这个  一份合同
I'm here 'cause of this. It's a deal.
需要找个人帮忙看看
It just needs a little taking care of.
如果是这样
Well, in that case,
你还是径直把它扔进垃圾桶吧
just go ahead and throw it in the trash,
我才不会为你工作  这辈子也别想
'cause I don't work for you and I'm never going to.
我觉得你没搞清楚状况
Uh, I don't think you understand.
我不是求你  而是要求你
I'm not asking. I'm assigning.
我们之前说好的
This is part of our deal.
我和你没什么协议
I don't have any deal with you.
她没有告诉你  是吧
She didn't tell you, did she?
谁没有告诉我什么
Who didn't tell me what?
唐娜
Donna.
我们做了笔交易  你当我的律师
We made a deal where you're my lawyer.
你们都要为我工作
I'm holding you both to it.
如果你对此有什么疑问...
And if you got a problem with that...
去找她
Take it up with her.
唐娜  你找我有什么事
Donna. What can I do for you?
楼下有辆豪华轿车
You can get your ass into the limo
等着你出发呢
that's waiting for you downstairs.
-我没叫豪华轿车  -我知道你没有
- I didn't call a limo. - I know you didn't.
罗伯特·赞恩叫的
Robert Zane did.
罗伯特想让我去哪儿
And where exactly is Robert sending me?
纽约州北部地区
Upstate New York.
他有点事想找人帮忙
He has some business he needs help with.
所以不管他有什么事  速战速决
So whatever needs fixing, fix it fast.
你翻了我的内衣抽屉了吗
Did you go through my underwear drawer?
虽然我很喜欢这种晨间小游戏
As fun as that would have made my morning,
但没有  亚历克斯
no, Alex, I didn't.
我把你出差需要的东西
I bought you a bag with exactly everything
都放这个包里了
you'll need for as long as you're gone.
你怎么知道
And how could you possibly know
我都需要些什么
that's everything I'll need?
因为罗伯特需要我这样
Because Robert needed me to.
而且别忘了我可是唐娜
And because I'm Donna.
轿车可不会一直等你  亚历克斯
Limo's not gonna wait all day, Alex.
早上好  哈维  有什么事
Morning, Harvey. What can I do for you?
你能告诉我大卫·福克斯不是我的客户吗
You can tell me David Fox isn't my client.
抱歉  我不能  因为他就是你的客户
I'm sorry, I can't do that, because he is.
一整年  免费服务
For a year. Free of charge.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
那是因为你授权给我
It's possible because you empowered me
让我和他协商
to negotiate with him,
这就是事成需要付出的代价
and that's what it took to get it done.
你准备什么时候把你这个
And when were you gonna tell me
绝妙的主意告诉我
about this brilliant idea of yours?
我之前就把他名字
I already did tell you
加到你的客户名单里面了
when I added him to your updated client roster.
你知道我从来不看什么
You know damn well I don't read
更新的客户名单
my updated client roster.
好吧  你说得对
Okay. You got me.
我就是想看看当他找上门来
I just wanted to see the look on your face
然后你意识到你别无选择时
when he came to you and you realized
脸上的表情
you didn't have a choice.
就像这样
And there it is.
-你觉得这很好笑吗  -不  哈维
- You think this is funny? - No, Harvey.
我不觉得
I don't.
我之所以没告诉你的真正原因
And the real reason I didn't tell you
是因为我知道你会表现得很孩子气
is because I knew you'd react like a child.
但我用你给我的授权
But I made a deal that you gave me
达成了一个协议  因为你知道
the authority to make because you knew
你自己搞不定
you couldn't come to one yourself,
所以不管你现在是什么感觉
so whatever it is you're feeling,
都给我忍着  为团队做一次贡献
suck it up, take one for the team,
把任务完成了
and get this thing done.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
* See the money, wanna stay for your meal *
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
* Get another piece of pie for your wife *
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
* Everybody wanna know how it feel *
*所有人都想见见那景象*
* Everybody wanna see what it's like *
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
* I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind *
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
* Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money *
*好了*
* All right *
*退开点  我要跳舞*
* All step back, I'm 'bout to dance *
诉讼双雄
第八季  第七集
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
* The greenback boogie *
希拉  我知道我们在努力要孩子
Sheila, I know we're trying to conceive,
但我现在没办法和你上床
but I can't have sex with you right now.
我刚吃了个洋葱百吉饼
I just ate an onion bagel.
我打电话给你不是为了这个  路易
I'm not calling for that, Louis.
那你为什么给我的性爱手机打电话
Well, then, why'd you call on the sex phone?
因为我知道你会接  而我...
Because I knew you'd answer, and...
我等不及告诉你了
I just couldn't wait to tell you.
路易...
Louis...
我们中大奖了
We hit the jackpot.
什么大奖
What jackpot?
那个大奖
The jackpot.
-拿下出版者促销顾问公司了  -不是
- Publisher's Clearing House? - No.
我是说我们之后都不需要性爱手机了
I mean we don't need the sex phone anymore
因为...路易...
because... well, Louis...
你正中红心
you hit the bull's-eye.
天啊  我的精子没问题
Oh, my God! My boys can swim?
是的  我的国王
Yes, my king.
它们没问题
Yes, they can.
希拉  这真是太棒了  我们得告诉...
Sheila, this is amazing! We need to tell my--
路易...我知道你想昭告天下
Louis... I know you're gonna want to tell everyone,
但是在此之前  我希望你能做出保证
but, before you do, I want you to promise
保证先不把这事说出去
that we'll keep this between the two of us for a while.
等等  你的意思是不昭告天下
Wait, so you mean not tell anyone?
没错  就瞒一小段时间
Yeah, just for a while.
好的  希拉  稍等一下
Okay, Sheila, can you hold on a sec?
我有个电话进来了
I think I'm getting a call.
好了  只是个账单上的问题
Okay. It was just a billing question.
已经处理好了
All taken care of.
你刚刚在你那全玻璃的办公室里
You just jumped up and down
上蹿下跳了是不是
in your entirely glass office, didn't you?
没错  但我现在没跳了
Yes, but I stopped now.
那我们今晚见吧
Then I'll see you tonight.
我们可以好好庆祝一下
And we can celebrate properly.
格蕾琴  你来得正好
Ah, Gretchen. Good, you're here.
听着  我需要你起草...
Listen, I need you to file--
希拉怀孕了  是不是
Sheila's pregnant, isn't she?
该死  你怎么知道的
Oh, shit, how could you know that?
两分钟前  你接听了你的性爱手机
Two minutes ago, you were on your sex phone.
然后你开始像电影《浑身是劲》一样扭动
Then you started dancing up and down like "Footloose,"
手指下体
pointing to your nether regions.
还能是因为什么
What else could it be?
不能
Nothing else.
格雷琴
Gretchen.
我就要有孩子了
I'm gonna have a baby.
不敢相信我会这么说  路易
I can't believe I'm saying this, Louis.
但你会成为一个绝世好爸爸的
You're gonna be a world-class father.
百分之百
That I am.
而且我打算参与每个瞬间
And I intend to be a part of every moment,
所以我需要你帮我查查当接生员
which is why I need you to look into what it takes
需要准备些什么
to get certified as a midwife.
如果你觉得我会为你的孩子接生
If you think I'm gonna be midwife to your baby,
那你就大错特错了
you got a whole nother thing coming.
不  不是你  是我
No, not for you, for me.
-那我退出  -怎么  你觉得我搞不定吗
- And I'm out. - What? You think I couldn't do it?
-我知道你搞不定  -去你的  格雷琴
- I know you couldn't. - Well, damn it, Gretchen.
你是不是还想当奶妈
Do you want to be a wet nurse too?
你猜怎么着  如果可以的话我愿意
You know what? I would if I could.
你刚刚才说我会成为一个很棒的父亲的
And you just said that I would be a great father.
所以你到底要不要帮我
So are you gonna help me with this or not?
好吧  路易  我会帮你查查的
All right, Louis. I'll look into it.
但就像我之前说的
But it's like I said before.
你会成为一个很棒的父亲的
You're gonna be a great father.
好吧  大卫
Okay, David.
你到底想要什么
What exactly is it that you want?
因为你在买楼的时候绝对不会需要我
Because you certainly don't need me to hold your hand
握着你的手给你打气
while you buy a building.
如果楼主是我最大的对手我就需要了
I do if that building's owner is my biggest rival.
因为那位楼主知道你是怎样的一个王八蛋
And because that owner knows what an asshole you are,
所以你需要确保他不知道
you need to make sure he doesn't know
你就是那位买家
you're the one doing the buying.
所以我才付你这么多钱
See, this is why I'm paying you the big bucks.
等等  我不需要付你钱
Oh, wait, I'm not paying you anything.
我说清楚  你下次再嘴欠我可不客气
Just so we're clear, you get one of those.
因为我也许的确得代理你
Because I may have to represent you,
但我不用忍受你的臭嘴
but I don't have to tolerate your mouth.
那我也和你说清楚
And just so we're clear,
这个人也许是个混蛋  但他不傻
this guy's a douche, not an idiot.
他会盯着我  看是不是我想买那栋楼
He's gonna be looking for me to try to buy that building,
所以我需要你机灵点
so I need you to be smart.
这是你第二次提到这个了
And that's the second time you've brought this up.
不禁让我思考
Which makes me wonder
这里面是不是有什么猫腻
if there's something going on here,
因为隐瞒买家可能并不违法
because hiding a buyer isn't illegal,
但也绝对有违法的可能
but it sure as hell can be.
唯一的猫腻就是
The only thing going on here
约翰·毕洛斯手里有块糖
is that John Billows has a piece of candy
而我想把它从他手中抢过来
and I want to take it from him.
还有一件事
One other thing.
这是我的生意
This is my business.
所以如果你要接手  那你就得搞定
So you take this on, you get it done,
不然你就干脆不要接手
or you don't take it on at all.
罗伯特  很高兴见到你
Robert. Good to see you.
谢谢你能来  亚历克斯  旅途如何
Thanks for coming, Alex. How was the drive?
风景不错  我猜
Scenic. Let me guess.
这地方的主人是我们的委托人
The owner's our client.
这地方是我的
The owner's me.
实话实说  罗伯特
I gotta tell you, Robert,
我可没想到你会把酿酒当做爱好
making wine's not exactly the hobby I pictured for you.
这不是爱好  是投资
It's not a hobby, it's an investment.
结果现在反而亏本了
And right now, it's netting less than zero.
我能帮上什么忙吗
What can I do to help?
不如我先带你参观一下
Why don't we first start with a little tour?
萨曼莎  我能跟你说句话吗
Samantha, can I talk to you for a second?
当然  你想说什么
Sure, what's on your mind?
关于你和亚历克斯还有罗伯特和哈维
You and Alex and Robert and Harvey...
哈维接了一个他不想要的案子
Harvey's got a case that he doesn't want,
但没人说过
but there's nothing that
不可以找外援帮把手
says that he can't get a little outside help on it.
别告诉我你想让我来帮哈维
Don't tell me you're trying to give me a leg up with Harvey,
因为你不会说  我也不会答应的
because you wouldn't do that and I don't need it.
说的没错  我不会现在开口的
You're right. I wouldn't.
不过迟早有一天  你和亚历克斯之中
But sooner or later, it's gonna be either you or Alex
会有一个人的名字被挂在公司那堵墙上
who go up on that wall next,
不管最后上墙的是谁
and no matter who goes up there first,
另外一方都不可能开心的
the other team isn't gonna be happy about it.
但如果我们在这之前就已经统一战线的话
But the more we're bonded as a family before that happens,
那之后我们能和睦相处的可能性就更大了
the more likely we'll stay a family after it does.
那我就只有一个问题了
Then I just have one question.
你说哈维不想
When you said Harvey doesn't want
但又不得不接下这个案子
to take the case but he has to...
-没错  -为什么
- He did. - Why?
因为我跟大卫·福克斯达成了一个协议
Because I struck a deal with David Fox,
但是哈维受不了他
and Harvey can't stand him.
-你能忍他吗  -我也不怎么受得了
- Can you? - Not particularly.
那你得在我去拜访大卫·福克斯之前
Then why don't you get me up to speed
先帮我补补课了
before I go pay a visit to this David Fox.
这酒怎么样
Well?
-其实我更喜欢精酿啤酒  -别扯了
- I'm more of a craft brew-- - Oh, save the bullshit.
我知道这酒难喝  这就是问题所在
I know. It tastes like ass. That's my problem.
所以你想让我来炒了你的酿酒师
So you want me to fire your winemaker?
不  我想让你去追查那个
No, I want you to go after the son of a bitch
迟迟不把我订的木桶送过来的混蛋
who didn't deliver the barrels that I paid for.
他害得我只能把酒保存在这些铁桶里
Because I had to let my wine stay in these vats,
然后我的酒就变成了你端着的那杯醋
and it turned into that vinegar you're now holding.
谁会想来买醋喝
And no one's interested in buying vinegar.
我这一季的葡萄都浪费了
I lost my entire harvest!
该死的
Shit.
你打电话
What did the guy say
催木桶的时候他怎么说的
when you called about the barrels?
他说明天就到
That they'd be here tomorrow.
然后明日复明日  就是不见桶
And tomorrow. And tomorrow.
而这附近的酒厂已经全部顺利收到桶了
And meanwhile, all my neighbors got their barrels just fine.
我就觉得这件事肯定
Which makes me think there's more going on here
没那么简单
than it looks like.
你觉得这是因为种族歧视
You think this is about race?
从我在银行看到的那些眼神
I think, between the looks I got at the bank
在市场上遭到的冷遇
and the cold shoulder I got at the market
还有现在这件事情看来
and now this...
像是同一部电影多次上演
You've seen this movie before.
选角不同
Different cast,
地点不同
different location,
但剧本该死的一模一样
but the same damn script.
罗伯特  如果这就是事情的真相
Robert, if that's what's going on here,
我不觉得诉讼会对这些人有什么影响
I'm not sure a lawsuit is gonna get these guys to back off.
我不是说他们是白人这个问题
Look, I'm not saying they're wearing white robes.
最关键的是他们想把我排挤出去
I'm saying they're trying to keep me out of the country club.
你想怎么办
What do you want to do?
我想让他们知道
I want to send a message
如果他们再敢这么做
that if they try this shit again,
他们的小团体就将不复存在了
there's not gonna be a country club.
大名鼎鼎的哈维·斯佩克特进了我的门
The great Harvey Specter walking through my door.
现在我知道我很厉害了
Now I know I'm a big deal.
你没有我即将提供的
Not as big as the deal
那份协议厉害  毕洛斯先生
I'm about to offer you, Mr. Billows.
我已经喜欢上你了
Oh, I like you already.
那你肯定也会喜欢上我的委托人的
Then you're really gonna love my client.
桑塔纳地产
Santana Developers.
他们是西南部一家很有前途的
They're an up-and-coming real estate firm
房地产公司  还有你也很幸运
from the southwest, and, fortunately for you,
他们对你在自由大道的重建项目
they've taken an interest in your redevelopment project
很感兴趣
on Liberty Avenue.
是吗
Have they, now?
那很遗憾  因为这个项目并不出售
Well, that's a shame, 'cause it's not for sale.
我也从没听说过什么西南部的公司
And there's no southwest firm that I've never heard of.
好吧  算你厉害
All right. You got me.
我的委托人跟迪拜政府联系密切
My client's associated closely with government of Dubai.
他们并不想公开这件事
A fact they'd rather not announce,
所以为了保密
and, in exchange for that secrecy,
他们愿意给你开出如下条件
they're willing to offer you this.
还是感谢你能前来
Thank you for your time.
约翰  这可比市价高四分之一
John, that's 25% over market value.
而且是现金交易
All cash.
我说过了  我不会卖的
And I told you, I'm not selling.
更别说是卖给大卫·福克斯
Least of all to David Fox.
好吧  约翰  听着
All right, John, look-- -
好吧  你确实值得赞赏
All right, look, I'll give you credit.
我是说  你果然名不虚传
I mean, you do live up to your reputation.
编一个幌子
'Cause a fallback straw man
这招确实我都没想过
is something even I never thought of.
如果你确实听闻过我的名声
And if you really knew my reputation,
你就会知道这个幌子只是我的第一步
you'd know a straw man is just my first move.
你不会想看见
You don't want to see
我的下一步的
what I'm gonna come at you with next.
我猜你会想断掉我的资金
Well, I believe you'll try to cut off my financing.
但是我的合伙人都在中国
But my partners are in China.
我和他们可是十年的交情了
And I've been in bed with them for ten years.
他们毫无疑问会信任我
They trust me implicitly.
慢走  斯佩克特先生
Good day, Mr. Specter.
替我向大卫·福克斯问好
My regards to David Fox.
路易  难以置信
Louis, I can't believe
你居然这么快就在这里订到了位置
you got us a reservation here so quickly.
希拉  你马上就是我儿子的母亲了
Sheila, you're gonna be the mother of my son.
你想去哪儿我都要带你去
I'm getting you in wherever you want to go.
-儿子  -女儿也不错
- Son? - Or daughter.
那这杯就敬不管是儿子还是女儿
Well, here's to watching either one of them
我们都会看着他们在芭蕾课上跳舞
take ballet lessons and tap
还要学指挥棒
and learn to twirl the baton.
天呐  我还能教他接力跑
Oh, my God, I get to teach him the baton.
简直等不及  所以我才想有个儿子
I can't wait. It's why I want to have a boy.
我等不及是因为我们要组建一个家庭了
And I can't wait because we're gonna be a family.
全家人时时刻刻都在一起
And we're gonna do everything together.
早晨一起穿戴洗漱
We're gonna get ready in the morning together.
还能一起度假
We're gonna go on vacations together.
我们还能去布鲁哈训练营看他
We're gonna get to visit him at Camp Brucha
看他跑出来  穿着那小小的
and see him come running out in his little--
等等  布鲁哈训练营
Wait a second. Camp Brucha?
希拉  不  我知道我告诉过你那里的小鬼
No, Sheila, I know I told you that the kids there
把我的内裤全烧了
burned all my underwear,
但我要告诉你  我因此变得更坚强了
but I'm telling you, it made me stronger.
路易  我不管你的什么内裤
Louis, your underwear isn't what I'm talking about.
我是说布鲁哈  那是个犹太人训练营
I meant Brucha is a Jewish camp.
-对啊  怎么了  -我到现在才知道
- Yeah, so what? - So it never occurred to me
你想以犹太人的方式教养我们的孩子
that you'd want to raise our child Jewish.
当然了
Of course I do.
我以为这是不言而喻的
I thought it went without saying.
就像对我来说不言而喻的是
Just like I thought it went without saying
我们不会在教养方式上贴任何标签
that we wouldn't raise them anything.
-你怎么会这么想  -好吧  路易
- Why would you think that? - Okay, Louis.
你的父母会做何感想
How would your parents feel
假如我们要以天主教的方式养育孩子
if we said we were gonna raise our child Catholic?
正是如此
Exactly.
如果我们要以犹太教养孩子
That's how my parents would feel
我父母就会是这样的感受
if we raised our child Jewish.
是  但这是不一样的
Yeah, but it's different.
不  对我来说是一样的
Not to me, it isn't.
-希拉  -拜托  路易
- Sheila-- - Louis, please.
今晚我们本是来庆祝的
This is supposed to be a celebration.
你就不能先把这事放一边么
Can't you just let it go?
当然  希拉
Of course, Sheila.
这事就当没发生过
Consider it gone.
迈尔士·纽顿
Miles Newton.
哪位
Yes?
我是亚历克斯·威廉姆斯
My name is Alex Williams.
我的委托人是罗伯特·赞恩
I represent Robert Zane.
-委托人  -没错
- Represent? - That's right.
他要告你违约
He's suing you for breach of contract.
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
我告诉他了这只是笔误
I told him it was a clerical error.
但这笔误让他赔了一个季度的收益
And that error cost him his yield for the season.
听着  我还告诉过他我会
Look, I also told him that I'll comp him
提供明年他需要的所有木桶作为补偿
all the barrels that he needs next year to make up for it.
有没有明年都还是个疑问
There may not be a next year
因为你骗走了我委托人的钱
because you cheated my client out of money,
现在你要还他那些骗走的钱
and now you're gonna pay him back,
加上他折损的收益
plus his lost revenue,
以及其他任何我能套在你头上的损失
and any other damages I can hang on you.
如果是我骗了他
If I cheated him,
那为什么我要给新来的家伙
then why would I give the new guy in town,
也就是你的委托人更低的折扣
your guy, a cut-rate deal?
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我另外的客户能多付5%
My other clients paid 5% more.
你的委托人才是那个占了便宜的
Your client was the one who actually got a break.
打七折
A 30% discount.
其他葡萄酒商知道你这么做么
And did the other vintners know you were doing that?
我们这是一个共同体  威廉姆斯先生
We're a community up here, Mr. Williams.
自己人保护自己人
We protect our own.
他们给了那个新来的家伙折扣
So they gave the new guy a break,
他们承受了损失
and they took the hit,
你却要往我脸上砸个官司
so you want to slap me with a lawsuit?
来啊  我倒要看看谁笑到最后
Go ahead, and we will just see who wins.
瞧瞧这是谁在法律图书馆里埋头苦干
Look at you sweating it out in the law library
像个大学新生似的
like a first-year.
我都不知道你会读书呢
I didn't know you could read.
我只看带图的
I'm just looking at the pictures.
你为什么不让我帮你
Then why don't you let me help you
想想怎么搞定那个大楼
figure out how to get that building.
你说什么
Excuse me?
唐娜觉得你也许需要我帮你
Donna thought you could use some backup
解决大卫·福克斯的案子
dealing with David Fox.
-唐娜说的还是你自己来的  -什么意思
- Donna did, or you did? - What does that mean?
意思就是你想给我留个好印象
It means you want to impress me
当时候到了  我还能给你投票
so when the time comes, I'll vote for you.
那你可得听好了
Well, let me tell you something,
这绝对没可能
that's never gonna happen.
我心里清楚的很
I know that.
我来这儿只是因为我可以给你提供
And I'm here because I just might have
一个解决福克斯案子的法子
a solution to your Fox problem.
你要么选择相信我  要么自己使劲琢磨
So you can either trust me or you can figure out
怎么搞定这个案子吧
how to get out of this yourself.
但我得说一句
But for the record,
不是我做的每件事都要求回报的
not everything I do comes with a price tag.
这是唐娜的主意吧
This was Donna's idea?
是的
Yeah, it was.
好吧  不如你先坐下
Well, then, why don't you sit down,
我给你捋一遍
and I'll bring you up to speed.
我有个更好的主意
I have a better idea.
不如我坐下告诉你
Why don't I sit down and tell you
我们该怎么赢下那个大楼
how we're gonna get that building.
还顺利吗
How did it go?
和设想的一样
Exactly as planned.
既然这样  我们喝杯酒来庆祝庆祝
In that case, why don't we have a drink to celebrate,
剩下的事情留着明天再说好了
and then we'll take care of everything tomorrow.
前提是你有啤酒或苏格兰威士忌
As long as you have a beer or some scotch,
我可不要喝那个醋味儿的鬼东西
because I'm not drinking any more of that vinegar shit.
别担心
Don't worry.
我也不喝
Neither am I.
罗伯特  我想问问你
Robert, I gotta ask.
你是个喝威士忌的  也是个律师
You're a scotch guy. You're a lawyer.
怎么就想到去买个葡萄园呢
Why come up here to buy a vineyard?
是我的姐姐
My sister.
她几年前去世了
She died years ago.
我们以前一起喝葡萄酒
We used to drink wine together,
对年份  单宁什么的一窍不通
and we didn't know shit about vintage or tannins.
我们只知道自己喜欢喝的是什么
We just knew what we liked.
现在当我喝葡萄酒时  我就会想起她
And when I drink wine, I think about her.
我不知道你还有个姐姐
I didn't know you had a sister.
你现在可不是知道了嘛
Well, now you do.
去年和瑞秋合作了一个案子
I worked a case with Rachel last year,
我就更想她了
got me thinking about her even more.
然后我意识到
And I realized...
我希望更想念她一点
I like thinking about her even more.
敬你对姐姐的思念
Then here's to making sure you're thinking of her
直到白发苍苍
till you're old and gray.
没错
Got that right.
谢谢你抽空见我  埃斯特
Oh, thanks for making time for me, Esther.
我真的非常感激
I really appreciate it.
我得说  路易
I have to tell you, Louis,
自从你告诉我那喜讯后我就一直笑容满面
I haven't stopped smiling since you told me the news.
你告诉爸妈了吗
Have you told Mom and Dad?
实际上这就是我想跟你谈话的原因
Actually, that's the reason I wanted to talk to you.
-好吧  -希拉和我之前谈过
- Okay. - Sheila and I were talking.
我们不准备把孩子当成犹太人抚养
We're not raising the baby Jewish.
我需要你帮我和爸妈解释这个
I need you to help me explain that to Mom and Dad,
而且我得知道你觉得他们会有多沮丧
and I need to know how upset you think they'll be.
要是他们下半辈子
How much would it upset you
都不再和你见面了你什么感觉
to be ostracized by them for the rest of your life?
说实话  这不是我能想到的最糟糕的事
Tell you the truth, I could think of worse things.
路易
Louis.
这会让他们崩溃的  你明知道这个
It would crush them, and you know it.
你是个犹太人
You're Jewish.
你的孩子也应该是犹太人
You should raise your children Jewish.
等等  等等
Wait a second, wait a second.
你也这么想
You feel the same way too?
这是你和希拉的事
I think this is between you and Sheila.
我的意见无关紧要
It's not up to me.
但你要听实话的话
But if you want the truth,
我一直以为你要有孩子的话
I always thought if you ever had kids,
他们会像我和你以及我的孩子
that they would go to Camp Brucha
一样去布鲁哈训练营
like mine did, like you and I did.
我知道  我也这么想  记得吗
I know. I do too. Remember?
* 因为 *
* Because... *
* 在布鲁哈训练营 *
* We're all mishpucha *
* 我们都是一家人 *
* Here at Camp Brucha *
不管怎么说  这都不可能了
Anyway, that's not gonna happen,
因为我跟希拉提起布鲁哈
because the way this whole thing started,
从而引发这事时
when I brought up Brucha to Sheila,
她差点呛到自己
she nearly choked on her water.
等等  这是她的主意
Wait a second, she's driving this?
当然是她的  你以为我愿意这样吗
Of course she is. You think I want this?
我就提了提夏令营的事
I just said the goddamn camp pledge.
那你要跟她说说你的感觉
Then you need to tell her how you're feeling.
我试过了
I tried talking to her about it.
她明显不愿意听
She made it clear she didn't want to,
所以就变成现在这样
and here we are.
路易  我想跟你聊聊杰弗里
Louis, I want to talk to you about Jeffrey.
杰弗里是个混蛋
Jeffrey's an asshole.
不  他不是  路易
No, he's not, Louis.
他是我孩子的父亲
He's the father of my children,
我们的婚姻分崩离析
and the reason our marriage fell apart
不是因为他对我做的事
wasn't because of what he did to me
而是因为那些他没有和我做的事
but because of what he didn't do with me.
表达他对吃白饭有什么感觉
Express how he felt about you being the breadwinner.
对
Yes.
所以要是你要我帮你
So if you want me to help you
把这事告诉爸妈  我会的
break the news to Mom and Dad, I will,
但只有你告诉希拉你的感受后
but I'm not gonna do it
我才会那么做
until you tell Sheila how you're feeling.
你们有什么事
All right, what do we have here?
我来说吧
I'll tell you what we have.
我有个房子  我不想卖掉它
I got a building; I don't want to sell it;
这两个就来找你哭诉
and these two are in here crying to you.
你没有律师
You don't have a lawyer?
我用不着律师
I don't need a goddamn lawyer.
我们没有哭诉
We're not crying.
我们在此代表社区
We are representing the community.
因为那房子建造于1896年
Because that building was built in 1896,
我们只想申请一道临时限制令
and all we're asking for is a TRO
冻结房子到地标委员会作出决定为止
until the landmark commission can make a decision.
等等
Give me a break.
他们不是代表社区
They're not representing the community.
他们是大卫·福克斯的律师
They're representing David Fox.
我没说他是我的委托人
I did not say he was my client.
即便他是我的委托人  那也不意味着
And even if he did, that doesn't mean
这和此事有关
this is connected to that.
那这件事呢  福克斯先生支付给
How about the fact that Mr. Fox has been shoveling
我最大的租户每月上万美金
my biggest tenant tens of thousands of dollars
来延续租期  好让我没法把他赶出去
a month to stay in his lease so I couldn't kick him out?
这有关系吗
Is that connected?
-什么  -法官阁下
- What? - Your Honor.
那些金钱是为了偿还一笔不相干的债务
Those payments are repayments for an unrelated debt.
胡说  皮特·明托
Bullshit. Peter Minto doesn't have
兜里一个子也没有
two pennies to rub together,
更别说借给大卫·福克斯几万美金了
much less tens of thousands to loan David Fox.
其他人的个人财务状况
And the details of someone's personal financial arrangements
不关你的事
are not your business.
够了
That's enough.
你们俩想把这个和地标委员会
You two want to push this up the hill
扯上关系  随你们的便
with the landmark commission, be my guest,
但我看不出为什么要
but I see no reason to stop this man
阻止这个人同时赚钱
from making a living in the meantime.
你们的限制申请驳回
Your restraining order is denied.
好吧  我们要做的是
Okay, what we need to do--
你怎么知道
How the hell did you find out
那些钱的事
about those payments?
我来说吧
I'll tell you how.
你背着我去找福克斯
You went to Fox behind my back.
不  我是在帮你
No. I had your back.
你两手空空  我给你找了点筹码
You had nothing. I brought you something.
那筹码刚刚炸了我们一脸
Well, that something just blew up in our faces,
因为他在用那些钱
because he's been using those payments
洗钱  搞事
to launder money, peddle influence,
或者进行天知道什么犯罪
or God knows what other crime.
所以我才不告诉你
And that is exactly why I didn't tell you,
唐娜告诉我你不信任他
because Donna told me you don't trust him.
我不信任他这点你说对了
You're damn right I don't trust him.
因为他那种人隐藏金钱时
Because when a man like that hides money,
绝不是他在偷偷做慈善
it's not because he's secretly donating to Goodwill.
哈维  他是我们的客户
Harvey, he is our client.
他不是
No. He's not.
-你不能不管他  -我能
- You can't just drop him. - Yes, I can.
因为我才不关心唐娜的交易
Because I don't give a shit about Donna's deal.
我不会代理对我当面撒谎的人
I'm not representing a client that lies to my face!
怎么了  纽顿先生
What's the matter, Mr. Newton?
你看着不太高兴
You don't look happy to be here.
我是不高兴
I'm not.
因为我不喜欢收传票
I don't appreciate being subpoenaed.
如果你不喜欢那个
Well, if you don't appreciate that,
你肯定更不会喜欢这个
you're definitely not gonna appreciate this.
你要起诉我的客户故意诈骗吗
You're accusing my client of intent to defraud?
确实如此  不是吗
That's what he did, isn't it?
我什么也没干
I didn't do anything
不过是稍稍延迟了运送你木桶的时间
except be a little bit late with your barrels.
你用折扣诱惑我得客户
What you did was entice my client with a discount,
破环他的产量
then sabotage his yield
因为你知道其他酒商能让你赚回钱
because you knew the other vintners would make you whole.
-我客户才没有这样  -他就是
- My client did no such thing. - Yes, he did.
昨晚他当我的面承认了  而现在
He admitted it to my face last night, and now,
我们不打算起诉
instead of a lawsuit,
而是刑事指控
you're looking at criminal charges.
刑事指控  你疯了吗
Criminal charges? Are you out of your mind?
他们不能这样  对吧
They can't do this to me, can they?
好好看看他的脸
Look at his face.
你就知道我们可以
It says we can.
刑事指控还便宜了你  狗娘养的
It should be more than that, you son of a bitch.
你到底有什么毛病
What the hell is your problem?
你想知道我的问题吗
You know what my problem is?
我这类人面临的最古老的问题
The oldest problem in the book for a man like me.
现在我要了结了它
And I'm putting a stop to it right now.
种族  你以为这是关于种族吗
Race? Race, is that what you think this is about?
我知道这就是症结
I know that's what this is about.
你这自以为是的混蛋
Oh, you pompous piece of shit.
-迈尔士  -不  别阻止我
- Miles. - No, no.
我不会乖乖坐着让他这样指责我
I am not gonna sit here and let him accuse me of that.
你想知道你为什么没拿到你的木桶吗
You want to know why you didn't get your barrels?
因为你不值
Because you don't deserve them.
-终于说出来了  -不不不
- And there it is. - No, no, no, no.
我们家族世世代代都在那些葡萄园里工作
See, our families have worked those vineyards for generations,
你以为你可以大摇大摆地
and you just come waltzing in here
带着你华尔街的臭钱进来
with your Wall Street money,
好像你是园主一样
acting like you own the place,
你来这里才多久  十分钟都不到
and you've been here for, what, ten minutes?
我们一辈子都在这里
We've been here our whole lives.
在你之前的那家伙只是有一年不太顺利
You bought out that man before you
你就买了他的股份
after he had one down year.
我们不会放过你的
And we're not gonna let you get away with it.
随便你怎么想
You tell yourself whatever you want.
但你说对了一件事
But you're right about one thing.
我是个不好惹的狠角色
I'm a big, bad motherfucker,
而且我要来喝光你们的奶昔
and I'm here to drink your goddamn milkshake.
让我猜猜  萨曼莎告诉你我要干什么了
Let me guess, Samantha told you what I'm about to do.
没错
Yeah, she did.
所以她背着我和你结盟了
Oh, so she keeps shit from me but shares it with you.
别把这事赖到她身上
Don't make this about her.
她只是从心所欲  和你一样
She does what she wants, just like you do.
-你和她一伙了  -我和自己一伙儿
- You're taking her side? - I'm taking my side.
也许你撒手不管这个案子了
Because you may be done with this case,
但她会继续处理
but she's gonna keep working on it
因为不像你  她在乎我的名声
because, unlike you, she cares about my reputation.
你觉得我不在乎你吗
You think I don't care about you?
你现在的地位就是拜我所赐
You're in your position because I put you there.
不  哈维  我取得的成就都我应得的
No, Harvey, I'm in my position because I fucking earned it!
如果你想谈谈你做过的事
Now, if you want to talk about things you did,
你同意我去协商这个交易
you authorized me to negotiate this deal,
如果你现在退出  福克斯会告诉全世界
and if you don't honor it, Fox is gonna tell the world,
那我下次再试着与别人达成协议时
and how's that gonna go the next time
还会有人信任我吗
I try to come to an agreement with anyone?
没人会听他的话  因为他这人没有信誉
It'll go fine because he has no integrity.
-不会有人信他  -行
- Nobody will believe him. - Okay.
那让我说得更明白一点
Let me put this in words that you'll understand.
我有信誉
I have integrity.
如果你让他走  我就成了骗子
You let him go, you're making me a liar.
你想说说骗子的事吗
You want to talk about a liar?
他当着我的面撒谎了
He lied to my face.
其他的客户也有
And so have a thousand other clients.
你不过是在伺机解约他
You were just waiting for an opportunity to let him go.
因为我们一开始就不该接他的案子
Because we never should've taken him on in the first place.
但我们接了  而且如我所说
Well, we did, and like I said,
你放弃了他  我就成了骗子
you drop him, you're making me a liar.
我不在乎世界上其他人知不知道
And I don't care if the rest of the world knows it or not.
你知我知
You'll know it, and I'll know it.
现在你该干嘛干嘛去吧
Now, you go ahead and do what you want.
反正你一向如此
You always do anyway.
路易  真是意外  我刚在看
Louis, what a surprise. I was just reading.
听着 希拉  我们需要谈谈
Listen. Sheila... we need to talk.
关于什么
About what?
我想让我们的孩子信犹太教
I want to raise our child Jewish.
路易  我以为我们之前说好了
Louis, I thought we talked about this.
不  希拉  我们没有
No, Sheila, we didn't,
因为我们在庆祝
because we were celebrating,
而你让我不要提这事
and you told me to let it go.
我试过就此罢休
And I tried to let it go,
但后来我和艾斯特谈了谈
but then I talked to Esther.
现在我没法不去想这事了
And now I can't.
我们说好了不告诉别人
Okay, so you talked to Esther
然后你转身告诉了艾斯特
after you said we wouldn't tell anyone yet?
是的  因为她是我的家人
Yes, I did, because she's my family.
我懂了  所以你和你妹妹
I get it, so you and your sister
深入地讨论了希拉  这个异族姑娘
have a long conversation about Sheila, the shiksa.
希拉  不是这样的
Sheila, it's not like that.
艾斯特帮助我意识到
Esther helped me realize that
我不在乎我父母怎么想
I don't care what my parents think.
或你父母怎么想
I don't care what your parents think.
我只在乎什么对我最重要
It's what's important to me.
那对我重要的东西呢
And how about what's important to me?
所以我想和你商量
That's why I want to talk this out.
因为我不想以后为这事埋怨你
Because I don't want to end up resenting you for this.
我也不想埋怨你
And I don't want to resent you either,
不如你告诉我为何信犹太教对你这么重要
so why don't you tell me why this is so important to you.
因为犹太教是我的一部分
What's so important is that it's a part of who I am.
天主教也是我的一部分
And being Catholic is a part of who I am.
但你说你不信教
But you said you were not religious.
你也说过
And so did you.
这就是我想跟你解释的地方
That's what I am trying to explain to you.
犹太教对我来说不仅仅是宗教
Being Jewish isn't just a religion to me.
更是我的血统
It's in my blood.
你觉得天主教对我来说不是吗
And you don't think it's the same for me?
-不 我不这么想  -那你根本就没明白
- No, I don't. - Then you don't get it.
当我说我父母不喜欢这样的时候
Because when I said my parents wouldn't like this,
我其实是想说  养育我的人
what I meant was, the people who raised me,
我的血亲们  费了好大力气
who are my blood, have had a hard enough time
才接受我不再信教这件事
accepting the fact that I don't practice anymore.
我不想再与他们产生分歧
And I don't want to separate myself from them
不想告诉他们我的孩子
by telling them that my child
会和我们所有人都不一样
is going to be different than all of us.
希拉  我不能就这么放弃
Sheila, I can't just rip this out of me.
路易  我没有叫你放弃
Louis, I'm not asking you to rip it out of you.
我只是不想你在孩子的宗教问题上这么绝对
I just don't want to raise our child one way or another.
你知道吗  对我来说  这是同一件事
You know what, to me, it's the same damn thing.
那我对你无话可说了
Then I don't know what to tell you.
我也一样
Neither do I.
萨曼莎  我能和你聊聊吗
Samantha, can I talk to you for a minute?
我感觉好像没有聊聊那么简单
Looks like you need more than that.
我想劝哈维别放弃福克斯的案子
I tried to talk Harvey out of dropping Fox,
但我不确定有没有说服他
but I'm not sure I convinced him.
-然后呢  -我告诉他你说
- And? - I told him you said
不管怎样你会继续做这个案子
you'd keep working on the case anyway.
真可笑  我可没这么说过
That's funny, because I didn't say that.
是  你的确没说过
No. You didn't.
但我告诉他你说过的原因是
But the reason I told him you did is--
因为你已经答应福克斯了
Because you gave Fox your word.
而且即使哈维不同意接  我也会接
And even if Harvey doesn't live up to it, I can.
没错
Exactly.
看起来我要接着工作了
It looks like I've got some more work to do.
因为我不能让你变成个骗子
Because I'm not gonna make a liar out of you.
-谢谢你  萨曼莎  -不用谢我  唐娜
- Thank you, Samantha. - No need to thank me, Donna.
如果我有困难你也会帮我的
I'm sure you'd do the same for me.
路易  怎么了
Louis, what's going on?
你一周来我这这么多次可不寻常
It's not usual for you to come in so many times in one week.
哈维又怎么了
What did Harvey get into now?
和哈维无关  我是要说希拉
This isn't about Harvey. It's about Sheila.
我要你帮我说服她让我们的孩子信犹太教
I need you to convince her to raise our children Jewish.
路易  我不会这么做的
Louis, I'm not going to do that.
为什么
Why not?
我知道上次她来找过你
I know she came to see you that time.
你以为我不知道吗
Did you think I wouldn't find out about that one?
不  我知道你会发现的
No, I assumed you would find out
我跟她说了让她告诉你
when I explicitly told her to tell you about it.
如果你能命令她告诉我的话
Well, if you can order her to do that,
为什么你不命令她让孩子信犹太教就好了
why can't you order her to raise our children Jewish?
你这算哪门子的心理医生啊
What kind of therapist are you?
路易
Louis.
我知道我以前告诉过你
I know I've told you this before,
我也知道你不相信
and I know you refuse to believe me,
但我父母就是曾经生活在纳粹德国的犹太人
but my parents were Jews in Nazi Germany,
他们当时有理由
and there was a point for them
放弃犹太教
where they discussed renouncing their Judaism
以保命
for a chance to save their lives.
但他们没有
They didn't.
所以我非常理解
So I understand as much as anyone
保留犹太人身份对于任何人的价值
the value of maintaining a Jewish identity.
-但是  -但是对于我来说
- But? - But, to me,
犹太教的核心是家庭
the heart of Judaism is family.
你想说什么
What're you saying?
我是说  如果你们关于孩子的宗教问题
I'm saying, if you can't be on the same page
无法达成一致
about how to raise your children,
也许你们应该考虑不要孩子
maybe you should discuss not having them.
太晚了
It's too late for that.
那么  路易
Then, Louis,
我认为你们一起做决定
I would say it's more important
是更为重要的
that you make a decision together
比决定的内容更加重要
than what that decision is.
谢谢你  斯坦
Thanks, Stan.
不用谢  路易
You're welcome, Louis.
在我们讨论别的之前还有一件小事
And there's just one more small matter before we move on.
什么事
What's that?
Mazel tov是犹太语的祝福语
祝你好运  我的朋友
Mazel tov, my friend.
祝你好运
Mazel tov.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
我给你个机会冷静一下
I gave you a chance to calm down.
罗伯特  我们需要聊聊
Because, Robert, we need to talk.
是的
We do.
讨论一下怎么让他们付出代价
About how we're gonna make them pay.
没错
That's the thing.
我们应该好好想想这件事
I think we should try to work this out.
你是在开玩笑吗
Are you goddamn kidding me?
罗伯特  他承认自己犯了罪
Robert, he admitted to a crime
来让我们相信他说的是实话
to convince us he was telling us the truth.
因为他可能相信自己的疯话
Because he probably believes his own bullshit.
我不管他相信什么
Well, I don't care what he believes.
如果我是白人
There's no way, if I'm white,
我们根本就不会遇到现在这种情况
we're in this situation right now.
我没有说你错了
I'm not gonna tell you you're wrong.
但是你对这种情况的处理方式不对
But you are wrong about how to handle this situation.
什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
我们应该相信他说的话
It means we take him at his word.
好
Okay.
假设你是对的
Let's say that you're right
这更和我的钱有关  而不是我的肤色
and this is more about my money than the color of my skin.
不管是什么原因  我不会让这个王八蛋
I'm not gonna let that son of a bitch
就这么把我赶出去
push me out no matter what the reason.
我已经忍气吞声太多年了
I've been putting up with this shit
比你出生的时间还长
for more years than you've been on this earth,
我已经接受处理这种事的方式
and I've accepted that the way to deal with it
就是把我自己的一部分深藏起来
is to bury a part of myself.
现在我再也不用这样做了
Well, I don't have to do that anymore,
而且你得听我的话
and you're gonna do what I say.
不  先生  我不会听你的
No, sir, I'm not,
因为这个世界已经够糟了
because the world's a shitty place
我不会让它变得更糟
and I'm not gonna make it worse.
我才不管你是不是我老板
And I don't give a shit if you're my boss.
我现在是你的律师
I'm your goddamn lawyer.
你要么就接受我的建议
And you're either gonna take my advice
要么就另请高明
or you can hire someone else.
那你立马叫车  现在就滚蛋
Then call yourself a car, and get the hell out of here.
我会自己处理
I'll handle it myself.
我希望你是来告诉我事情办好了
I hope you're here to tell me you got it done.
我再给你最后一次机会
I'm here to give you one last chance.
我知道你给彼得·明托打钱了
'Cause I know about the payments
毕洛斯也知道了
to Peter Minto, and so does Billows.
见鬼
Shit.
他知道多少
Well, how much does he know?
我不是来这讨论他知道什么的
I'm not here about what he knows.
我是来讨论我不知道的  因为我问过你
I'm here about what I don't, because I asked you
有没有暗中交易  你当着我的面说没有
if something shady is going on, you lied to my face,
而我还没跟你解约的唯一原因是
and the only reason I haven't dropped you yet
唐娜为你做了担保
is Donna gave you her word.
你根本就不明白
You know what, you wouldn't understand.
我明白洗钱是怎么回事
I understand money laundering,
了解了你的为人之后
and, knowing the kind of man you are,
我确信你就是在洗钱
it's exactly what's going on here.
你根本一点都不了解我的为人
You know, you don't know shit about the kind of man I am.
那你现在就告诉我
Then tell me right now.
彼得·明托到底给你什么条件
What the hell is Peter Minto giving you
来交换你每月支付10000美元
in exchange for $10,000 a month?
能代表你很荣幸  大卫
It was nice representing you, David.
不是他给我什么条件
It's not what he's giving me.
是他给过我什么
It's what he gave me.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
当时我13岁  身无分文
I was 13 years old. I didn't have any money.
我想抽烟
I needed a pack of cigarettes.
我就从明托商场偷了一包
So I took one from Minto's Market.
然后我一想  我来都来了
And then I thought, you know, while I'm at it,
不如再顺手偷点别的东西
I might as well take a bunch of other shit.
-他没起诉你  -他没有
- He didn't press charges. - No, he didn't.
他让我干活偿清
But he did make me work it off.
后来我意识到他在呵护我成长
Next thing I knew, he took me under his wing.
听着  我给他钱是因为如果我不给
Look, I gave him that money because if I didn't,
他就会破产
he'd go out of business,
如果我买不下这商场
and if I can't get this building,
他也会破产
he's gonna go out of business anyway.
你为什么不一开始就告诉我这些
Why didn't you just tell me this in the first place?
跟我不想任何人知道这事的理由相同
For the same reason I don't want anyone to know it.
我需要人们相信我是一个冷酷无情的人
All right, I need people to believe that I'm ruthless.
难道你不应该让人们觉得你很忠诚
Well, wouldn't you rather have people know you're loyal
而不是让他们觉得你是个混蛋吗
than have them think you're an asshole?
彼得·明托教会我如何绅士地做生意
Look, Peter Minto taught me how to do business
但是他濒临破产
as a gentleman, but there's a reason
而我越做越大是有原因的
he can't keep his business alive and I can.
好吧
Well...
我不认同你的想法
I can't say I agree with you...
但是我会帮你买下商场
but I'll get you your building.
唐娜  这么晚还没睡
Donna. You're up late.
我还没睡是因为你说
I'm up late because you said
这事现在应该解决了
this thing would be done by now,
而我还没听到你的消息
and I haven't heard from you,
这让我想知道  现在什么情况了
which makes me wonder... how's it going?
我告诉你什么情况
I'll tell you how it's going.
我不仅没跟亚历克斯增进感情
Instead of getting closer with Alex,
相反我让他打包走人了
I had to send him packing.
什么  为什么会这样
What? How did that happen?
因为我是他的客户
It happened because I'm his client
但我说的话他一句也不听
and he wouldn't listen to a word I said.
听着  我想说一件事
Look, I want to say something,
但是我有些犹豫  因为通常情况下
but I'm hesitant to say it because it's not something
我是不会对经营合伙人说这话的
I would normally say to a managing partner.
说出你的想法
Speak your mind.
我不知道你们发生了什么  但我知道
Well, I don't know what the issue is, but I do know
每次有律师和客户闹翻的时候
when a lawyer and a client have a falling out,
更通常的情况是
more often than not, it's because
客户不听律师的话
the client wouldn't listen to the lawyer,
而不是反过来
not the other way around.
尤其是当这名律师是
In particular, when that lawyer
亚历克斯·威廉姆斯的时候
is Alex Williams.
-说完了吗  -就这些
- Is that all? - That's it.
我希望你的事能顺利解决  罗伯特
I hope you get whatever it is taken care of, Robert.
你还在参与福克斯的案子吗
Are you still working the Fox case?
我相信唐娜告诉你我还在
I believe Donna told you I was,
而唐娜从不骗人  怎么了
and Donna's no liar, why?
我要重新接手这案子了
Because I'm back in.
-谁让你改变了主意  -是福克斯
- What changed your mind? - Fox did.
事实证明福克斯支付那些资金是因为
Turns out those payments were because Peter Minto
彼得·明托是他的导师
was Fox's mentor.
他不是在洗钱
He wasn't laundering anything.
他是想拯救那家商场
He was trying to save that market.
所以其实他还真是在做慈善
So he was basically donating to Goodwill after all.
看来是的
I guess he was.
等一下
Wait a minute.
慈善
Goodwill.
-公益  -你想到什么了
- Public good. - What do you got?
任何项目都有公益的要求
There's a public good requirement for any project.
没错  这个项目的公益是
Yeah, and this one has it covered
补贴住宅
with the subsidized housing.
因为住宅  是他的中国投资商来买单
Because that way, his Chinese investors have to cover it.
你怎么知道这个
How do you know that?
因为我有他们协议的副本
Because I got a copy of their agreement,
如果是住房类公益  投资商要承受损失
and if that good is residential, they take the hit.
如果是贸易类公益  毕洛斯承受损失
If it's commercial, Billows does,
而明托商场是贸易类公益
and Minto's Market is a commercial public good.
意味着我们需要做的是告诉中国投资商
Which means all we need to do is tell those Chinese investors
他们信赖的合作伙伴在暗中设计他们
their trusted partner's been screwing them.
这样一来毕洛斯要么失去合作伙伴
And Billows either loses his partners
要么自己出钱买单
or foots the bill himself.
这样就会让他左右为难
which puts him between a rock and a hard place.
只能就是把商场卖给大卫·福克斯
And his only way out is to sell to David Fox.
你看
Look at that.
我们合作的多好
We make a pretty good team, don't we?
可能吧
Maybe.
但还有一个问题
But the only problem is,
这样一来整个项目福克斯会亏很多钱
it makes this whole project a money loser for Fox.
那能怎么样  他说了他一直在补贴明托
So what? He said he's been subsidizing Minto anyway.
那是私下说的  这是在公众视野里的
Privately. This is in the public eye,
意味着人们会觉得
which means everyone's gonna think
他不是软弱就是愚蠢  我跟你说
he's either soft or stupid, and I'm telling you,
这人最怕的就是这两件事
it's that man's worst nightmare.
你想怎么做
What do you want to do?
-你能联系上中国投资商吗  -可以
- Can you get to the Chinese? - I can.
你去搞定他们  我来搞定大卫·福克斯
You handle them, and I'll handle David Fox.
计划不错
Sounds like a plan.
你确定你能搞定他们吗
Are you sure you can handle them?
你敢打赌我可以
Ni gan dadu wo keyi.
好吧  但你能搞定他们吗
Yeah, but can you handle them?
-又怎么了  -我打过来是想说对不起
- What now? - I'm calling to say I'm sorry.
我失控了
I lost my shit.
事实是  如果我在你的位置上
Truth is, if I was in your position,
可能我和你的感受一样
I'd probably feel the same way.
你不在我的位置上
Well, you're not in my position.
你是我的律师
You're my lawyer.
如果我不听你的
And if I'm not gonna listen to you
继续自己处理这件事
and go ahead and handle this thing myself...
那你就是自己的傻瓜委托人了
You've got a fool for a client.
差不多吧
Something like that.
我想我可能有方法解决这件事
Anyway, I think I may have a way through this.
你有什么想法
What you got?
你说过你想
You said that you wanted
完全相信他们
to take them at their word.
如果我们这么做  问题是
If we did that, the problem is,
我们在和一个感觉受到威胁的社区打交道
we're dealing with a community that feels threatened.
所以我在想
So I was thinking,
保险弥补了我今年的亏损
insurance covers my losses this year.
明年  我的酒桶免费
Next year, my barrels are free,
然后我可以建立一个社区品酒室
and then I can build a community tasting room
我们所有人可以一起分享
that we all can share.
你真慷慨  罗伯特
That's very generous of you, Robert.
介意我问下是什么说服了你吗
Mind if I ask you what brought you around?
两件事  和一个朋友的谈话
Two things. A conversation with a friend.
还有呢
And?
我成长的地方  社区就是一切
Where I grew up, community was everything.
我们关系紧密
We were tight and close,
不信任外人
mistrusting of outsiders, and...
如果有人进入而且做了我对他们做的事
if someone had come in and done what I did to them...
社区不会容忍的
The community wouldn't have taken too kindly to it,
不论他们是什么肤色
no matter what the color of their skin.
所以我想也许我们到底并没有太大的分别
So I thought maybe we're not so different after all.
明白了
Copy that.
所以你明天要向他们提议这些事
So you're gonna propose all of that to them tomorrow.
罗伯特  我认为如果你将成为
Robert, I think if you're gonna
这个社区的一份子
be a part of this community,
我们应该一起向他们提议
we ought to propose it to them together.
那你快给我回来
So get your ass back up here then.
还有亚历克斯  不许再叫我傻瓜
And Alex... don't ever call me a fool again.
欢迎回家  路易
Welcome home, Louis.
那个是
Is that...
没错
Yes, it is.
你妈妈的烤布丁
Your mother's kugel.
你怎么
How did you...
-你妹妹打来了  -我猜猜
- Your sister called. - Don't tell me.
她想说服你以我的方式看待它
She tried to convince you to see it my way.
不是的  路易  她打过来 跟我说
No, Louis, she called to tell me,
无论发生了什么
whatever happens,
她爱我
she loves me
她想欢迎我来这个家庭
and wants to welcome me to the family.
所以烤布丁是为什么
So why the kugel?
因为我妹妹永远不会为我做这个
Because my sister never would have done that for me.
路易  也许现在我没有准备好
Louis, I may not be ready
做这个决定
to make this decision right now,
但是我们所挣扎的是
but what we were really struggling with
如何去融合我们的身份
was how to blend our identities.
所以我想  更好的办法去做这件事
So I thought, what better way to do that
可以从做烤布丁开始
than by starting with kugel?
如果我们要做这个
Well, if we're gonna be doing that,
我不明白为什么今年我们不能
I don't see why we can't also have
有个圣诞树呢
a Christmas tree this year.
-你愿意接受圣诞树  -是的
- You'd be open to that? - Yes, I would.
因为我今天去见了利普希茨医生
Because I saw Dr. Lipschitz today.
希拉  他提醒了我
Sheila, he reminded me
家庭是一切的基础
that the foundation of everything is family.
所以我在想
So I've been thinking...
停住别说了  我也在想
Stop right there. I've been thinking too.
你上次问了我
You asked me last time.
这一次我来问你
I'd like to ask you this time.
路易·马洛·利特
Louis Marlowe Litt...
你愿意娶我吗
Will you marry me?
是的  希拉  我愿意
Yes, Sheila, I will.
早安
Morning.
我刚正在想我们的婚礼
I was just thinking about our wedding.
路易
Louis...
我想也许我们可以把它变成一个目标
I was thinking maybe we can make it a destination.
现在我不想谈我们的婚礼
I don't want to talk about our wedding right now.
为什么
Why not?
我例假来了  我没有怀孕
I got my period. I'm not pregnant.
-但是那个测试说你  -那个是假阳性
- But the test said that you-- - It was a false positive.
你知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
这只是路上的一个绊脚石
It's just a bump in the road.
如此而已
That's all this is.
只是一个停顿
Just a pause.
宝贝  还有积极的一面
And sweetie, there's a bright side.
因为它给了我们一个机会
Because it gave us a chance
去进行非常艰难的交流
to have really tough conversations.
从这个方面来说  当我们真的有了孩子
And that way, when we do get pregnant,
我们以后会有孩子的
and we will get pregnant,
我们不会再像从前一样没有准备好
we'll be ready in a way that we weren't ready before.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我会好起来的
I will be.
拜托告诉我你没和艾斯特以外的人说这事
Please tell me you didn't tell anyone other than Esther.
我和格雷琴说了
I told Gretchen.
你得去告诉她我没怀
You need to untell her that.
你好  罗伯特
Hello, Robert.
我想你打给我是有好消息要告诉我
I assume you're calling me with good news.
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
你不知道我对这种事有第六感吗
Don't you know by now I have a sense for these things?
我只是想打来说谢谢  唐娜
I just wanted to call and say thank you, Donna.
我们解决了
We worked it out.
你和亚历克斯
You and Alex?
我  亚历克斯  这儿的所有人
Me, Alex, everybody up here.
这一切不会发生
And it wouldn't have happened
如果没有你提醒我自己干的蠢事
without you calling me on my shit.
你知道他们怎么说医生是最坏的病人的吗
You know how they say doctors make the worst patients?
律师也是一样的情况
Same goes for lawyers?
不  律师更糟糕
No. Lawyers are much worse.
我想他们是的
I guess they are.
这就是我很开心有像你这样的朋友的原因
Which is why I'm glad I have someone like you.
打来感谢我
Wow... calling to thank me,
重视我的领导地位  给我一个讨人喜欢
valuing my leadership, and giving me
喜欢的绰号  罗伯特  要是不小心
an endearing nickname-- Robert, if we're not careful,
我们可能就成朋友了
we could become full-blown friends.
这个险我愿意冒
Oh, that's a chance I'm willing to take.
回见  伙计
See you soon, Pops.
一样  伙计
Right back at you, Red.
我理一下  你是要告诉我
Let me get this straight, you're telling me
你可以给我弄到大楼  但是
you can get me the building, but it's gonna
要留下彼得为我做事
cost me more to keep Peter in business
比我之前要付的还要多
than I was paying in the first place?
而且
And on top of that,
全世界还都要知道
the whole world's gonna know about it,
因为毕洛斯一定会说出去
because Billows is gonna make sure they know it.
你是在变本加厉地和我作对吗
Are you trying to stick it to me even more?
我是想让你在作出决定前
I want you to know the cost of this thing
清楚你要付的代价
before you make a decision.
这简直扯淡
This is bullshit.
-大卫  -该死的
- David. - God damn it.
你本可以做到更好的
You could have done better.
你本可以在一开始就把事情都告诉我
And you could've told me the full ---ing story
就不至于让我只有两天解决这个问题的
before I only had two days to stop it.
所以要么我丢人
So either I look like a sucker
要么让帮我启动事业的人失业
or I let the guy who gave me my start go out of business.
帮彼得·明托一把
Helping Peter Minto stay in business
不丢人
doesn't make you a sucker.
世人会觉得丢人
It does to the world.
大卫  条件就是如此
David, the deal is what it is.
如果我能做更好  我会的  但是不行
If I could make it any better, I would, but I can't.
那你会怎么做
What would you do?
作为你的律师  我会说
As your lawyer, I'd tell you
理智点
get your emotions in check.
条件很烂  也不是好策略
It's a shitty deal and a stupid move.
但如果是我  我就接受
But if I were in your shoes, I'd take it.
接受吧
Take it.
我从未想到我会这么说
You know, I never thought I'd be saying this,
但是  我敬你
but... you earned my respect.
你看起来像是刚吃了只金丝雀的小馋猫
Well, don't you look like the cat that ate the canary.
没错  那金丝雀名叫罗伯特·赞恩
I do. And that canary's name is Robert Zane.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
他打来电话开始使劲夸你
He called you and started unleashing compliments
感觉把你当家人一样
like you were his family.
你怎么知道
How'd you know?
他有时候就那样
He gets like that sometimes.
我本来想
Well, I was thinking that I wanted
我也该把他当家人一样
to treat him like family right back,
也许你可以给我些意见
and maybe you could give me some advice
看看给他送什么礼物
on getting him a gift.
不  唐娜  别送礼物
Oh, no, Donna. You don't want to do that.
怎么  为什么
What? Why not?
他最不会接受礼物了
He's a terrible gift receiver.
不会吧
You're kidding.
我送过他一本《风的传人》
I once gave him vintage copies
一本《杀死一只知更鸟》
of "Inherit the Wind," "To Kill a Mockingbird,"
他生日送了他一本《十二怒汉》
and "Twelve Angry Men" for his birthday.
第二年  我在他抽屉发现了它们
The next year, I found them in his drawer
连包装都没拆
with the bow still tied on.
他是律师  那些书就是讲律师的
He's a lawyer. They're books about the law.
-你跟他说了吗  -没有
- Did you say something? - No.
我拿回来了  他都没发现
I just took them back. He didn't even notice.
我打算等他退休的时候再送给他
I'm gonna regift it to him when he retires.
怎么
What?
哈维跟他正相反
Harvey's the opposite.
-很会接受礼物  -很不会送礼物
- Great gift receiver. - Awful gift giver.
他的心是好的  但是两周后
Heart's in the right place, but two weeks in,
我就发现如果我
I realized if I ever really wanted
还想要个好生日礼物
to enjoy my birthday present,
就只能自己买了
I was gonna have to buy it myself.
现在还买吗
Do you still?
上次生日才买的
Got these for the last one.
32岁  如果你想知道的话
32, if you're wondering.
说曹操曹操到
Speak of the devil.
看看谁空手进来了
Look who's walking in empty-handed.
-说什么呢  -没什么  哈维
- What are you talking about? - Nothing, Harvey.
既然你们俩都在
Well, as long as you're both here,
你不仅关于福克斯说对了
you weren't just right about Fox.
关于一开始和他开战对了
You were right about taking him on in the first place,
在找她帮忙上也是对的
and you were also right about getting her to help me.
要不是我清楚他这个人  唐娜
If I didn't know any better, Donna,
我会以为他在道歉了
I'd say he's apologizing to you.
有趣  我以为他在向你道歉呢
That's funny, I was thinking he was apologizing to you.
这下我理解我们为什么都困惑了
Well, I can understand why we're both confused.
因为这个道歉太弱了
It's a pretty weak apology.
他连抱歉这个词都没用
He didn't even use the word "Sorry."
我觉得他都不知道有抱歉这个词
I don't even think he knows the word "Sorry."
-你俩说完了吗  -才开始呢
- Are you two finished? - We're just getting started.
搬个凳子  哈维
Take a chair, Harvey.
顺便给我们倒点喝的
And pour us a couple of drinks while you're at it.
要是我知道会这样
If I'd known this was gonna happen,
我就什么都不说  更别提说抱歉了
I wouldn't have said anything, much less "I'm sorry."
瞧瞧  他还是知道有这个词的
Ooh, look at that. He does know the word.
-只是不会用  -没错
- Yeah, just not how to use it. - Mm-hmm.
路易  你这一天跑哪去了
Louis, where have you been all day?
我需要陪陪希拉
I needed to spend some time with Sheila.
我有好消息
Well, I've got good news.
我给你找到了一个助产班
I found a midwife class for you.
原来你不是唯一一个想当
Turns out, you're not the only mid-aged white man
琨妮医生和医学女的中年白人
that wants to be Dr. Quinn, Medicine Woman.
真好
That's great.
但我需要你取消
But I'm gonna need you to cancel it.
路易  怎么了
Louis, what's wrong?
是误报
It was a false positive.
我们没有孩子了
We're not gonna have a baby.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
但这并不代表...
But that doesn't mean that she--
我知道  格雷琴
I know that, Gretchen.
我只是需要单独待一会儿
I just need a little time to myself.
我理解
Of course.
你不用在我面前故作坚强
You don't have to be strong for me, Louis.